dianomi.com 2019-12-25

# Privacy Policy - dianomi - intelligent customer acquisition

#### If you would like to go directly to dianomi’s opt-out status options, please click here.

**Introduction**

Welcome to Dianomi’s privacy notice. 

Dianomi respects your privacy and is committed to protecting your personal data. This privacy notice will inform you about how we use and look after your personal data when you visit our website and when we provide our services to you (regardless of where you visit from) and tell you about your privacy rights and how the law protects you. 

This privacy notice is provided in a layered format so you can click through to the specific areas set out below. Please also use the Glossary to understand the meaning of some of the terms used in this privacy notice.

  1. **IMPORTANT INFORMATION AND WHO WE ARE**
  2. **THE DATA WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU**
  3. **HOW IS YOUR PERSONAL DATA COLLECTED**
  4. **HOW WE USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA**
  5. **OPT-OUT**
  6. **COOKIE POLICY**
  7. **DISCLOSURES OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA**
  8. **INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS**
  9. **DATA SECURITY**
  10. **DATA RETENTION**
  11. **YOUR LEGAL RIGHTS**
  12. **GLOSSARY**

### **Important information and who we are**

**Purpose of this privacy notice**

This privacy notice aims to give you information on how Dianomi collects and processes, clients and users personal data through your use of the dianomi websites and dianomi network of publisher sites, including any data you may provide through this website when you sign up to our newsletter or request information about other products and services from Dianomi. It also describes how in the course of providing our services to our advertising clients we collect and use your personal data for analytical purposes and in order to deliver personalised advertisements for products or content you might be interested in.

This website is not intended for children under the age of thirteen (13) and we do not knowingly collect data relating to children. However, if children who are under thirteen (13) provide personal information to us, their parents or legal guardian can request us to delete this information from our records by sending us an email at **[datasubjectrights@dianomi.com](mailto:datasubjectrights@dianomi.com)**. 

It is important that you read this privacy notice together with any other privacy notice or fair processing notice we may provide on specific occasions when we are collecting or processing personal data about you so that you are fully aware of how and why we are using your data. This privacy notice supplements the other notices and is not intended to override them. 

**Controller**

Dianomi Limited, dianomi inc, dianomi pty, is the controller and responsible for your personal data (collectively referred to as "Dianomi", "we", "us" or "our" in this privacy notice).

Dianomi is made up of different legal entities, details of which can be found [here](https://www.dianomi.com/cms/contact/). This privacy notice is issued on behalf of the Dianomi Group so when we mention "Dianomi", "we", "us" or "our" in this privacy notice, we are referring to the relevant company in the Dianomi Group responsible for processing your data. Dianomi Limited is the controller and responsible for this website. 

If you have any questions about this privacy notice, including any requests to exercise your legal rights (including an opt-out mentioned in this privacy notice), please contact us at: [dpo@dianomi.com](mailto:dpo@dianomi.com)

**Changes to the privacy notice and your duty to inform us of changes**

This version was last updated on  and previous versions can be obtained by contacting us at: [dpo@dianomi.com](mailto:dpo@dianomi.com)

**Third-party links**

This website may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. When you leave our websites or network of publisher sites, we encourage you to read the privacy notice of every website you visit.

### **The data we collect about you**

If you do not fill in one of our forms, we do not know who you are, your address, your date of birth, your email address or your phone number.

Personal data, or personal information, means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. It does not include data where the identity has been removed (anonymous data).

We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you (as a user, advertiser or publisher) which we have grouped together follows:

**Identity Data** includes first name, maiden name, last name, username or similar identifier, date of birth and gender.

**Contact Data** includes billing address, delivery address, email address and telephone numbers.

**Financial Data** includes bank account and payment card details. (This only applies to our advertisers, publishers and X)

**Transaction Data** includes details about payments to and from you and other details of products and services you have purchased from us.

**Technical Data** includes internet protocol (IP) address, your login data, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform and other technology on the devices you use to access this website and our services. 

**Profile Data** includes your username and password, your interests, preferences, feedback and survey responses.  

**Usage Data** includes information about how you use our website, network of publisher sites, products and services. 

**Marketing and Communications Data** includes your preferences in receiving marketing from us and our third parties and your communication preferences.

We also collect, use and share **Aggregated Data** such as statistical or demographic data for any purpose. Aggregated Data may be derived from your personal data but is not considered personal data in law as this data does **not** directly or indirectly reveal your identity. For example, we may aggregate your Usage Data to calculate the percentage of users accessing a specific website, content. However, if we combine or connect Aggregated Data with your personal data so that it can directly or indirectly identify you, we treat the combined data as personal data which will be used in accordance with this privacy notice.

We do not collect any **Special Categories of Personal Data** about you (this includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health and genetic and biometric data). Nor do we collect any information about criminal convictions and offences.

**If you fail to provide personal data**

Where we need to collect personal data by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into with you. In this case, we may have to cancel a product or service you have with us but we will notify you if this is the case at the time. 

### **How is your personal data collected?**

We use different methods to collect data from and about you including through:

**Direct interactions.** You may give us your Identity, Contact and Financial Data by filling in forms or by corresponding with us by post, phone, email or otherwise. This includes personal data you provide when you:

  * Apply for our products or services as an advertiser or publisher
  * Create an account on our website
  * Subscribe to our service or publications
  * Visit a web page with our ad units
  * Click on a link in our ad units
  * Request marketing to be sent to you
  * Enter a competition, promotion or survey
  * Give us some feedback. 

**Automated technologies or interactions.** As you interact with our website or network of publisher sites, we may automatically collect Technical Data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns. We collect this personal data by using cookies, server logs and other similar technologies. We may also receive Technical Data about you if you visit other websites employing our cookies. Please see our cookie policy **** for further details. We record  your browsing behaviour when you visit websites on which our ads are displayed including which pages are visited. This can be used to target you with personalised advertising and for analytics purposes.

**Third parties or publicly available sources.** We may receive personal data about you from various third parties and public sources as set out below:

  * Analytics data
  * Demographic data
  * Industry
  * IP addresses

### **How we use your personal data**

Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:

  * Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with our publisher and advertiser clients and others.
  * Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests.
  * Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.
  * Providing our Service. To provide and manage our Sites and Services.
  * For analytical and insight purposes.
  * To register you as a new customer, advertiser, publisher
  * To process and deliver your order campaigns including:
    * Manage payments, fees and charges
    * Collect and recover money owed to us
  * To manage our relationship with you which will include:
    * Notifying you about changes to our terms or privacy policy
  * To enable you to partake in a prize draw, competition or complete a survey
  * To administer and protect our business and this website (including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data)  
  * To deliver relevant website content and advertisements to you and measure or understand the effectiveness of the advertising we serve to you
  * To use data analytics to improve our website, products/services, marketing, customer relationships and experiences
  * To make suggestions and recommendations to you about goods or services that may be of interest to you
  * To check the reputation of that IP Address (both then and later)
  * We need to use your IP address so we can geotarget our ads
  * For robot detection
  * For audit purposes
  * Legal compliance. To comply with applicable legal obligations, including requests from law enforcement or other governmental entities.

**Tracking and retargeting**

**For EEA users**

Dianomi does not cookie EEA users (and other users from countries were GDPR applies) for the purpose of behavioural targeting. Dianomi will serve ads to EEA users contextually and therefore will not require users’ consent for targeting purposes.

Apart from as stated above, generally we do not rely on consent as a legal basis for processing your personal data other than in relation to sending third party direct marketing communications to you via email and for behavioural targeting. You have the right to withdraw consent to marketing at any time by contacting us.  

**Purposes for which we will use your personal data**

**Marketing / Targeting**

We strive to provide you with choices regarding certain personal data uses, particularly around marketing and advertising. We have established the following personal data control mechanisms:

**Promotional offers from us -**

For users outside the EEA, We may use your Identity, Contact, Technical, Usage and Profile Data to form a view on what we think you may want or need, or what may be of interest to you. This is how we decide which products, services and offers may be relevant for you (we call this marketing). In most cases we will show you recommendations based on the context of the page and not on your personal data profile.

You will receive marketing communications from us if you have requested information from us or if you provided us with your details when you entered your details in one of our form 

**Third-party marketing**

Dianomi may also use third parties to serve ads.These third parties may collect information about your visits to this and other websites, your IP address, your ISP, the browser you use to visit our Website (but not personal information such as your name, address, email address or telephone number). They do this using their own cookies, clear gifs or other technologies. Information collected may be used, among other things, to deliver advertising targeted to your interests and to better understand the usage and visitation of our Website and the other sites tracked by these third parties.  This policy does not apply to, and we are not responsible for, cookies or clear gifs in third party ads, and we encourage you to check the privacy policies of advertisers and/or ad services to learn about their use of cookies and other technology. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [click here](https://www.networkadvertising.org/consumer/opt_out.asp) 

### **Opting out**

You can opt-out from marketing messages at any time by contacting us.You can also opt-out from our cookies for interest based ads by clicking on the button below.

You are opted in 

You are opted out 

**Opting out - Tracking**

If you have:

Opted Out: you have opted out of tracking (behavioural targeting), dianomi will no longer serve you with personalized content recommendations based on your Internet history.

Not Opted Out: in some cases dianomi will serve you personalized recommendations (behavioural targeting) based on your history, however dianomi serves mostly contextual recommendations.

Tracking mechanisms operate at the device and browser level, so if you would like to opt-out across all devices, you will need to do so on each device and browser individually.

### **Cookie Policy**

To enhance your online experience we use "cookies." Cookies are small text files placed by the Website in your computer's browser to make a user’s experience more efficient. Cookies, by themselves, do not tell us your e-mail address or other personal information. However, once you choose to furnish the Website with personal information (such as signing up to receive one of the offers made by our third party advertising partners), this information may be linked to the data stored in the cookie. We use cookies to understand Internet usage, enhance the performance of the Website, activate special web features and security mechanisms. In addition, we may use cookies to offer you products, programs or services which may be part of client retargeting campaigns.

You always have the option of setting your browser to warn you when a cookie is being accessed on your computer, to delete cookies that are currently on your computer or to decline cookies altogether. However, to take full advantage of the Website and its features, your browser will need to accept cookies.

Web beacons (also known as clear gifs) are small, invisible graphic images that may be used on the Website and in e-mails to collect certain information about your use of and activity with the Website and emails. If we combine cookies or clear gifs with or link them to any of the personally identifying information, we would treat this information in the same way we treat other personal information.

You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when websites set or access cookies. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this website may become inaccessible or not function properly. 

The law states that we can store cookies on your device if they are strictly necessary for the operation of this site. For all other types of cookies we need your permission.

This site uses different types of cookies which are listed in the below table. Some cookies are placed by third party services that appear on our pages.

Your consent applies to the following domains:   
www.dianomi.com, www.marketviews.com, my.dianomi.com, help.dianomi.com 

### Necessary Cookies

##### Necessary cookies help make a website usable by enabling basic functions like page navigation and access to secure areas of the website. The website cannot function properly without these cookies.

Name | Provider | Purpose | Expiry  
---|---|---|---  
IFAdisclaimer (for marketviews.com) | Dianomi | For directing a user to correct part of site | Session  
PHPSESSIONID | Marketviews | Set by the Advanced Polls plugin to detect and prevent duplicate poll votes  | Session  
_cfduid (x4) | Cloudflare | Security  (See the following for more info: <https://support.cloudflare.com/hc/en-us/articles/200170156-Understanding-the-Cloudflare-Cookies>) | 30 days  
cookielawinfo-checkbox-analytics | Dianomi, Marketviews | Accepted analytics cookies | 1 year  
cookielawinfo-checkbox-marketing | Dianomi, Marketviews | Accepted marketing cookies | 1 year  
cookielawinfo-checkbox-necessary | Dianomi, Marketviews | Accepted necessary cookies | 1 year  
player | Vimeo |  Necessary for the implementation of the Vimeo embedded player for video-content on the website.  (See the following for more info: <https://vimeo.com/cookie_policy>) | 1 year   
viewed_cookie_policy | Dianomi | Working of site | 1 year  
  
### Analytics Cookies

##### Analytics cookies help website owners to understand how visitors interact with websites by collecting and reporting information in a way that does not directly identify you.

Name | Provider | Purpose | Expiry  
---|---|---|---  
IFAdisclaimerGT (for marketviews.com) | Dianomi | For analytics and pushing to correct part of site | Session   
SESSION_KEY (for my.dianomi.com) | Dianomi | Log in tracking | Session  
Sites (for my.dianomi.com) | Dianomi | Site visitor tracking | Session  
_ga (x3) | Google | google analytics tracking | 2 years  
_gat_UA-187050-10 (x3) | Google | google analytics tracking | 1 minute  
_gid (x3) | Google | Registers a unique ID that is used to generate statistical data | 24 hours  
  
### Marketing Cookies

##### Marketing cookies are used to track visitors across websites. The intention is to display ads that are relevant and engaging for the individual user and thereby more valuable for publishers and third party advertisers.

Name | Provider | Purpose | Expiry  
---|---|---|---  
Visitor_[number] | Salesforce/Pardot | Site visitor tracking from Pardot | 10 years  
Visitor_[number]-hash | Salesforce/Pardot | Site visitor tracking from Pardot | 10 years  
_gads (on marketviews.com) | Google | Google ads manager – measuring and serving of ads | 2 Years  
dnt (on marketviews.com) | Dianomi | Indicates a user has opted out of targeting for interest based advertising | 5 years  
  
### Third Party Sites

##### Cookies placed by Dianomi via third party websites with that website owner’s permission:

Name | Provider | Purpose | Expiry  
---|---|---|---  
CLICK_ID | Dianomi | track users who have clicked on ads. | 3 years  
DIANOMI-CLICK-COOKIE | Dianomi | track users who have clicked on ads. | 3 years  
GED_PLAYLIST_ACTIVITY | flowplayer |  Playing of video ads | Session  
Set by a2.adform.net / track.adform.net | adform | Advertiser analytics | Set by Provider  
Set by ads.doubleclick.net | DoubleClick | Advertiser analytics | Set by Provider  
Set by ads.revjet.com | Revjet | Advertiser analytics | Set by Provider  
Set by bs.serving-sys.com | Serving Sys | Advertiser analytics | Set by Provider  
Set by pixel.adsafeprotected.com | Integral Ad Science | Advertiser analytics | Set by Provider  
Set by tps.doubleverify.com | Double Verify | Advertiser analytics | Set by Provider  
_cfduid (x3) | Cloudflare | Security | 30 Days  
ab | Neustar | user tracking | 1 year  
dnt (on marketviews.com) | Dianomi | Indicates a user has opted out of targeting for interest based advertising | 5 years  
session | Dianomi | dmp session id | 180 days  
session2 | Dianomi | track whether data synced with 3rd parties | 180 days  
sites | Dianomi | Which dianomi sites publishers, advertisers and staff have logged in to | 1 month  
third party cookie sync | Dianomi | Cookie Sync | 1 to 5 years  
u | Neustar | user tracking | 1 year  
  
**Change of purpose**

We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. 

Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.

### **Disclosures of your personal data**

We may share data or aggregated data with affiliates, subsidiaries or service providers for the purpose of delivering our services. 

Third parties to whom we may choose to sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our assets. Alternatively, we may seek to acquire other businesses or merge with them. If a change happens to our business, then the new owners may use your personal data in the same way as set out in this privacy notice. 

We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law.

### **International transfers**

We share your personal data within the Dianomi Group. This will involve transferring your data outside the European Economic Area ( **EEA** ).

Some of our External Third Parties in North America and APAC are based outside the European Economic Area ( **EEA** ) so their processing of your personal data will involve a transfer of data outside the EEA.

### **Data security**

We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality. 

We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.

### **Data retention**

**How long will you use my personal data for?**

The retention period will depend on the type of data concerned.  

  * Data in our DMP is retained for 12 months for users outside the US, Canada, Singapore, Hong Kong, India, then deleted.
  * Data relating to contracts might be kept for 7 years (ie the 6 years within which a legal claim could be brought under the contract plus one year for the claim to be dealt with).  
  * Financial data (eg payments) are kept for 12 years.  

### **Your legal rights**

You have the right to make a complaint at any time to the data protection authority about data protection issues. To know more, please contact your local data protection authority on [ this link.](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm)

We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach your local authority so please contact us in the first instance.

You have certain rights regarding your personal data, please [see here.](https://ico.org.uk/)

Where we rely on our legitimate interests to obtain and use your personal data then you have the right to object if you believe your fundamental rights and freedoms outweigh our legitimate interests.

Where processing is carried out based upon your consent, you have the right to withdraw that consent.

Your ability to exercise these rights will depend on a number of factors and in some instances, we will not be able to comply with your request e.g. because we have legitimate grounds for not doing so or where the right does not apply to the particular data we hold on you.

You should note that if you exercise certain of these rights we may be unable to continue to provide some or all of our services to you (for example where the personal data is required by us to comply with a statutory requirement, or is necessary in order for us to perform our contract with you).

Please contact us to update or correct your information if it changes or if the personal data we hold about you is inaccurate.

You may also exercise a right to complain to your Supervisory Authority. Please contact the Data Protection Officer if you wish to exercise any of your rights.

If you wish to exercise any of your rights, please [contact us](mailto:datasubjectrights@dianomi.com)

**No fee usually required**

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

**What we may need from you**

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity such as your driving licence or passport and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.

**Time limit to respond**

We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated. 

### **Glossary**

**LAWFUL BASIS**

**Network of Publisher Sites:** dianomi works with many publisher sites.

**Legitimate Interest** means the interest of our business in conducting and managing our business to enable us to give you the best service/product and the best and most secure experience. We make sure we consider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative) and your rights before we process your personal data for our legitimate interests. We do not use your personal data for activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you (unless we have your consent or are otherwise required or permitted to by law). You can obtain further information about how we assess our legitimate interests against any potential impact on you in respect of specific activities by contacting us

**Performance of Contract** means processing your data where it is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party or to take steps at your request before entering into such a contract.

**Comply with a legal or regulatory obligation** means processing your personal data where it is necessary for compliance with a legal or regulatory obligation that we are subject to.

**THIRD PARTIES**

**Internal Third Parties**

Other companies in the Dianomi Group acting as joint controllers or processors and who are based in the UK, US, Australia, Switzerland and provide IT and system administration services and undertake group reporting.

**External Third Parties**

Service providers acting as processors based inside or outside the EEA.

Professional advisers acting as processors or joint controllers including lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers based UK, US, Australia, Switzerland who provide consultancy, banking, legal, insurance and accounting services.

HM Revenue & Customs, regulators and other authorities acting as processors or joint controllers based in the United Kingdom who require reporting of processing activities in certain 

* * *

**Changes to This Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy is current as of the Effective Date set above.

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time, so please make sure to check it on a regular basis.
